You think that getting a health insurance
is just a formality and
a small mistake in completing that formality can
cause a loss of lakhs and crores to you and your family and to
avoid that loss, I have brought
information about the best health insurance plans 2025 which we have selected on the basis of a lot of research and claim
settlement.
Hello everyone, I am Soni Chauhan and
welcome to Policy Hub where we
make insurance simple, stress
free and easy to understand.
Book a free consultation now with Policy Hub's
IRDI certified experts for proper insurance related guidance.   The
link is given in the description below.   There are
many options available in the market.
And in 2025, family health insurance is
not just a game of sum insured; it is
flexibility, real benefits, claim
support and smart features that give you
true protection and peace of mind.
Be it young professionals or parents, they
need domestic or global coverage.  These
health insurance plans
fulfill all these criteria.
Before we proceed further, an important piece of information is that the
government has removed the
18% GST on health insurance premiums.
Due to which the health insurance
premium has now reduced to a great extent.
Okay let's come back to the topic.  Coming in
fifth place in the list of best health insurance plans 2025 is
Neevapa Aspire Titanium Plus,
which is suitable for people of all age groups.
Be it individual or
family insurance, it is specially designed
for young professionals
as this plan comes with inbuilt Miracle
Benefit which covers your maternity
expenses and also carries
forward the unutilized Miracle Sum Insured up to 10 times.
2R Plus
hospitalization is also covered in this health plan.  Whereas usually
in most of the health insurances,
24 hours and plus
hospitalization is mandatory for making a claim.  Booster
Plus benefit where you
can carry forward your unutilized sum insured.
Maximum up to 10 times.  Reashore Forever
where you can avail unlimited time restoration after the first claim.  This
means that after every claim,
your coverage will be refilled again and
again without paying any extra charges.
And the most attractive feature is Lock the Clock
benefit which locks your premium until there is a
claim in your policy.  Along with this,
in this plan you
can avail the facility of second medical opinion and e-consultation through network providers
unlimited times.  The Safeguard Plus add-on
covers your non-payable items and
also enhances your coverage according to inflation.
Additionally, add-ons like
Well Consult add-on for day-to-day OPD expenses and
Disease Management add-on to waive off the three-year waiting period for pre-existing conditions like BP and diabetes
are available.  As the Lock the Clock
benefit locks your premium.
But this does not mean that your premium will
not change.  Insurers revise their premiums from
time to time
for people of every age group according to the
inflation rate.  So, Neevapa Aspire
Titanium Plus offers all the benefits
that people
want in a basic policy these days.  Coming in
fourth place in the ranking of best health insurance plans is the
ICICI LB Elevate plan
which offers unlimited restoration after the first claim.
Inpatient treatment
for surrogate mothers who carry a baby
for another couple and oocyte donors who
donate their eggs
for fertility treatment for another couple is
covered under this health policy up to Rs 5
lakh and
you can also avail premium discount of up to 30% through wellness programs.
In this health insurance plan, sum insurance option is available from Rs 5 lakh
to unlimited sum insurance.  Power
Booster Benefit Add-on where you get a bonus of 100% of the sum assured
irrespective of the claim with no
maximum limit.  That means
your Unlimited Sum Ins Bonus will be increased.
You can cut the three-year waiting period for pre-existing conditions by opting for
Jump Start benefit.  You
can claim unlimited amount throughout your lifetime.   You
can cover delivery expenses, new born baby cover and vaccination expenses through Infinite Care, OPD expenses through BeFit and maternity benefit.  The thing to note here is
that you can avail Infinite Care only within 2 years of taking the policy.
This option will not be available later and
you will have to serve a minimum waiting period of 2 years to claim maternity benefit.
Now the
third one in the best health insurance
policy is Bajaj Allianz My Health Care
Plan which offers unlimited restatement
facility which is
available for related and unrelated diseases.
Maternity package expenses are covered up to Rs
1 lakh and baby care maximum up to Rs 50
lakh depending on your sum insured.
In this plan, you get up to 100% cumulative
bonus in a claim-free year and
outpatient treatment expenses are also covered
twice of your premium.  Home nursing
benefit is available according to Rs. 10,000 per week
and this help plan
also covers the expenses of prescribed external medical aids such as bases, scans, clutches, walkers, wheelchairs etc. up to Rs.
50,000.  And in case of death of the proposer, this
health insurance policy
waives off one year's premium for the remaining family members.
So that he can become financially stable
and continue his health insurance from next year.  There are also
some exclusive add-ons like Suicide/Loss of Income
cover, Major Illness and Accident
Multiplier where
extra sum insured is available in case of critical illness or accident
and International Emergency cover where the
company
covers the expenses of emergency hospitalization in a foreign country.  Before I proceed further,
I would like to remind you that you can
book a free consultation
with Policy Hub.  All our services are free of
cost and here we not only help you in choosing the best health
insurance policy according to
your needs and requirements and provide better
guidance but also provide proper support at the time of claim.
24*7 It will
take you just 1 minute to book a call.  The link
is given in the description below.  So let us
now talk about the rest of the two health insurance companies.
Tata AIG Medicare Premier Plan comes second in the Best Health Insurance 2025.
Tata Group rules the hearts of millions of Indians because of its trust, ethics and social
responsibilities.
This
health plan is a comprehensive and complete
health insurance that covers a wide range of sum
insured between Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore along with higher
outpatient treatment and dental OPD
expenses.  Also, Unlimited
Restoration, which works on both related and unrelated
diseases and
provides a cumulative bonus of up to 100%.  This health
insurance provides
you with global coverage along with domestic hospitalization.
Maternity expenses maximum up to Rs 1.2
lakh, delivery complications maximum up to Rs
25,000 and baby first year vaccination up
to Rs 15,000 along with animal bite
vaccination expenses and consumable
items are also covered up to the sum insured.
And if you have continuous hospitalization for more than 10 days, the
company also gives you a cash benefit of 1% of the sum insured.
All these benefits are
available as add-ons in most companies.  But you get all these benefits inbuilt in this health insurance plan.  The
thing to note here is that
maternity expenses will be
covered after a waiting period of 4 years and also its
newly launched plan Midi Select which is
quite reasonable and flexible.  Where
customers can modify the plan according to their needs.
And finally, the
number one company in the best health insurance category
is HDFC Ergo Optima Secure which is known for
its reliability, comprehensive coverage and
features which are genuinely beneficial from the customer's point
of view and has 15000
plus network hospitals with CSR of 99.16%
and ICR of 81%.  Optima Secure is quite famous
in the market for its Secure Benefit
which offers double coverage from the same day.
Plus benefit increases your sum and shot
by 100%.  Irrespective of
Claim Protect benefit covers all the non-payable
items which are normally
neglected by other companies and also offers facilities
like home care treatment, Ayush treatment.
Unique add-ons
like PD waiting period reduction,
unlimited restoration, OPD expenses
through Optima Well Being Rider and
maternity expenses are also covered.  If you
want to get a deeper insight into these five companies
, you can watch their complete review
on the end screen of the video.  And if you are
still confused about which of these
plans will be perfect for you.  Worry not,
just book a free consultation
with Policy Hub's IRDI certified advisors
who will help
you choose the best health insurance plan as per your needs and requirements.  The
link
is given in the description below.  So friends, these were the
best health insurance plans 2025.
All the plans are best in their category.
Whether you are a young professional, newly married
or want a secure future with your family.
A right health insurance plan
is the backbone of your financial safety net.
Which plan did you like the best?
Please tell us in the comment section.  And if you
found the video inspiring, please like, share and subscribe to the channel.
See you
in the next video with a new infatuation topic.
Till then stay safe, stay secure.